<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<clinical_study>
	<nct_id>NCT00812123</nct_id>
	<brief_title>Calcineurin Free Immunosuppression in Renal Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
	<brief_summary>
      The main purpose of this study is to obtain preliminary information on the efficacy, safety
      and cost of two regimens, Rapamycin / MMF / steroid therapy and Cyclosporine A Neoral / MMF /
      steroid therapy, used in the prevention of acute rejection following renal transplantation.
    </brief_summary>
	<detailed_description>
      This pilot study is designed to show differences in efficacy, safety and cost between the two
      regimens. Its main purpose is to provide information, if calcineurin free immunosuppressive
      treatment is a valuable alternative in the treatment of de novo kidney transplant recipients.
      Furthermore, by investigating the side effects in both arms it will be possible to decide, if
      the absence of calcineurin inhibition and lack of nephrotoxicity will outweigh the adverse
      effects of Rapamycin. With the obtained information it will be possible to plan a larger
      trial, which is warranted to compare the mentioned treatment regimens in more detail.
    </detailed_description>
	<condition>Kidney Transplantation</condition>
	<gender>All</gender>
	<minimum_age>15</minimum_age>
	<maximum_age>75</maximum_age>
	<inclusion_criteria>:

          -  Male or female patients between 15 and 75 years of age, regardless of race.

          -  Female patients of child bearing age agree to maintain effective birth control
             practice during the study.

          -  Patient has end stage kidney disease and is a suitable candidate for primary renal
             transplantation or retransplantation as assessed by the transplantation center.

          -  Patient has been fully informed and has given written or independent person witnessed
             oral informed consent.

        </inclusion_criteria>
	<exclusion_criteria>:

          -  Patient is pregnant or breastfeeding.

          -  Patient has a low immunological risk constellation, defined by receiving a kidney from
             a HLA-identical related living donor.

          -  Patient has a high immunological risk constellation, defined as having within the
             previous three years a measured PRA grade of ≥25% and/or having a previous graft
             survival shorter than 3 years due to rejection.

          -  Patient and donor have a positive T or B-cell crossmatch.

          -  Patient and donor are ABO incompatible.

          -  Age of donor &gt; 68 years.

          -  Cold ischemia time &gt; 36 hours.

          -  Patient has leucopenia, defined as having at transplantation less than 3000/mm3
             leukocytes.

          -  Patient has thrombocytopenia, defined as having at transplantation less than 75000/mm3
             thrombocytes.

          -  Patient is allergic or intolerant to cremophor RH 60 or structurally related
             compounds, steroids, Cyclosporine A Neoral, Rapamycin or MMF.

          -  Patient requires initial sequential or parallel therapy with immunosuppressive
             antibody preparation(s).

          -  Patient or donor is known to be HIV positive.

          -  Patient has significant liver disease, defined as having during the past 28 days
             continuously ASAT (SGOT) and/or ALAT (SGPT) levels greater than 3 fold of the upper
             value of the normal range of the investigational site.

          -  Patient with malignancy or history of malignancy ≥ 2 years, except non metastatic
             basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has been treated successfully.

          -  Patient has significant, uncontrolled concomitant infections and/or severe diarrhea,
             vomiting, or active peptic ulcer.

          -  Patient is taking or has been taking an investigational drug in the past 28 days.

          -  Patient has previously received or is receiving another organ transplant other than
             kidney.

          -  Patient is unlikely to comply with the visits schedule in the protocol.
      </exclusion_criteria>
	<criteria>
        Inclusion Criteria:

          -  Male or female patients between 15 and 75 years of age, regardless of race.

          -  Female patients of child bearing age agree to maintain effective birth control
             practice during the study.

          -  Patient has end stage kidney disease and is a suitable candidate for primary renal
             transplantation or retransplantation as assessed by the transplantation center.

          -  Patient has been fully informed and has given written or independent person witnessed
             oral informed consent.

        Exclusion Criteria:

          -  Patient is pregnant or breastfeeding.

          -  Patient has a low immunological risk constellation, defined by receiving a kidney from
             a HLA-identical related living donor.

          -  Patient has a high immunological risk constellation, defined as having within the
             previous three years a measured PRA grade of ≥25% and/or having a previous graft
             survival shorter than 3 years due to rejection.

          -  Patient and donor have a positive T or B-cell crossmatch.

          -  Patient and donor are ABO incompatible.

          -  Age of donor &gt; 68 years.

          -  Cold ischemia time &gt; 36 hours.

          -  Patient has leucopenia, defined as having at transplantation less than 3000/mm3
             leukocytes.

          -  Patient has thrombocytopenia, defined as having at transplantation less than 75000/mm3
             thrombocytes.

          -  Patient is allergic or intolerant to cremophor RH 60 or structurally related
             compounds, steroids, Cyclosporine A Neoral, Rapamycin or MMF.

          -  Patient requires initial sequential or parallel therapy with immunosuppressive
             antibody preparation(s).

          -  Patient or donor is known to be HIV positive.

          -  Patient has significant liver disease, defined as having during the past 28 days
             continuously ASAT (SGOT) and/or ALAT (SGPT) levels greater than 3 fold of the upper
             value of the normal range of the investigational site.

          -  Patient with malignancy or history of malignancy ≥ 2 years, except non metastatic
             basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has been treated successfully.

          -  Patient has significant, uncontrolled concomitant infections and/or severe diarrhea,
             vomiting, or active peptic ulcer.

          -  Patient is taking or has been taking an investigational drug in the past 28 days.

          -  Patient has previously received or is receiving another organ transplant other than
             kidney.

          -  Patient is unlikely to comply with the visits schedule in the protocol.
      </criteria>
</clinical_study>